A Guide to the Virginia Educational Media Association Records, 1952-2011 (ongoing)
Library of Virginia
- Series XIII. 2003 Addition (Accession 40363), 1963-2002.
  - Annual conference, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 5-6)
    Also includes 2 VHS and 1 audiotape.
  - Annual conference, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Annual conference, 2001 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Annual conference, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Awards and scholarships, 1998 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Awards and scholarships, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 11-12)
  - Awards and scholarships, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Awards and scholarships, 2001 (Box 21, Folder 14-15)
  - Board meetings, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Board meetings, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Board meetings, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 18-21)
  - Board meetings, 2001 (Box 21, Folder 22-23)
  - Board meetings, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Clinch Regional Conference, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Clippings, 2000-2001 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - C.W. Dickinson Jr. files (Box 21, Folder 27-29)
  - Handbook/membership directory supplement, 1999-2000 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Handbook/membership directory, 2000-2001 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Information Power, 1988-1989 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - James Regional Conference, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Joint conference, VLA/VEMA, October 1998 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Leadership Development Conferences, 1988-1989 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Leadership Conference, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Literature Conference, 2001 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Mediagram (some gaps), 1976-2001 (Box 22, Folder 9-21)
  - Miscellaneous VEMA directories, 1989-1992 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1963-2001 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous VEMA literature (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Motions book, 1976-1994 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Photographs (Box 22, Folder 26-28)
    Note: Additional photographs from this accession are found in boxes 23, 24.
  - Projecting VEMA in the 21st Century (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Potomac Regional Conference, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - The Public Librarian's Workout Book, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Rappahannock Regional Conference, 2000-2001 (Box 22, Folder 32-33)
  - Regional Directors Meeting, 29 July 2001 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Retreat, 7-8 May 1999 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Roanoke Regional Conferences, 2001-2002 (Box 22, Folder 36-38)
  - School Library Media Month certificates of recognition, 2000-2001 (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - School Library Media Specialist of the Year, 1997-2000 (Box 22, Folder 40-48)
  - School Library Media Specialist of the Year, 2001 (Box 23, Folder 1-7)
  - School Library Media Specialist training (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Shenandoah Regional Conference, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Student Media Festivals, 1985-2003 (some gaps) (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - VAECT miscellaneous, 1974-1975 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - VAECT newsletters, 1971-1975 (some gaps) (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - VEMA Journal (Vol. 1, No. 1; and Vol. 3, No. 1) (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Virginia Education Association materials, 1967-1975 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Virginia Journal of Education, 1908-1930 (gaps; some are partial photocopies) (Box 23, Folder 15-19)
  - York Regional Conferences, 2000-2001 (Box 23, Folder 20-21)
  - Loose photographs (Box 23, Folder N/A)
  - Loose photographs (Box 24, Folder N/A)
  - Oversize posterboards, circa 1986-1987 (Box 25, Folder N/A)
    Posterboards with VEMA information glued on, mostly cutouts from the Winter 1986/1987 and Summer 1987 issues of Mediagram.
- Series XIV. 2007 Addition (Accession 43479), 1999-2004.
  - Administrator of the Year Award, 2002 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Administrator of the Year Award (not selected), 2002 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Annual conference, 2003 (Box 29, Folder N/A)
    Binder of photographs from the conference.
  - Awards and scholarships, 2000 (Box 26, Folder 3-4)
  - Awards and scholarships, 2001 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Awards and scholarships, 2003 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Awards and scholarships (not selected), 2003 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Awards presentation banquet, 2002 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Ballots, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Ballots, 2002 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Ballots, 2003 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Board meeting, September 2001 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Board meeting, November 2001 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Board meeting, January 2002 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Board meeting, April 2002 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Board meeting, September 2002 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Board meeting, October 2002 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Board meeting, February 2003 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Board meeting, April 2003 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Dickinson Scholarship Award, 2002 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Dickinson Scholarship Award (not selected), 2002 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Helping Others Adjust the Sails, 2003 (Box 29, Folder N/A)
    Binder, forming part of Charlie Makela's entry as Media Educator of the Year.
  - Mediagram, Winter 2001/2002-Fall 2002 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Mediagram, Winter 2002-Fall 2003 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Photographs (Box 27, Folder 6-7)
  - Potomac Regional Conference, 27 March 2004 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Rutherford Memorial Award, 2002 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - School Library Media Specialist of the Year, 2002 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - School Library Media Specialist of the Year (not selected), 2002 (Box 27, Folder 11-13)
  - School Library Media Specialist of the Year, 2003 (Box 28, Folder 1-2)
  - School Library Media Specialist of the Year (incomplete applications), 2003 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - School Library Media Specialist of the Year (not selected), 2003 (Box 28, Folder 4-7)
  - Shenandoah Regional Conference, 4 May 1999 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Shenandoah Regional Conference, 6 March 2002 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - VEMA notepad (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - VEMA Summer Professional Development: Communication is Key, 15 July 2002 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Virginia State Reading Association Conference, 7-9 March 2002 (Box 28, Folder 12)
- Series XV. 2009 Addition (Accession 44424), 1990-1992, 2002-2009.
  - Annual conference, 2005 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Annual conference, 2006 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Annual conference, 2007 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Author visits/awards, 2005 and undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Ballots, 1991-1992 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Board meetings, 2007 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Board meetings, 2008 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Clinch Regional Conference, 28 March 2006 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Handbook/membership directory, 2006-2007 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - James Regional Conference, 15 March 2006 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Linking Libraries and Academic Achievement (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Mediagram, Fall 1990 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous clippings/correspondence, 2006-2008 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - National Library Legislative Day, 2006 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Potomac Regional Conference, 14 March 2007 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Rappahannock Regional Conferences, 2006-2008 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Research Foundation Paper: School Libraries Work!,2006, 2008 editions (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Roanoke Regional Conferences, 2005-2006, 2008-2009 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - School Library Media Month certificates of recognition, 2002-2007 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - School Library Media Specialist of the Year (Rappahannock Region), 2007 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Shenandoah Regional Conferences, 2006-2008 (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Technology Tools and Tips Boost Student Learning and AYP (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - The Third Great Virginia Teach-In: A Call to Teach, 18 March 2006 (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - VEMA Professional Workshop, 24 July 2006 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - VEMA Recognition as AECT affiliate, 27 July 2002 (Box 13, Folder 0007418008)
  - York Regional Conference, 2 May 2006 (Box 30, Folder 25)
- Series XVI. 2011 Addition (Accession 50225), 1991-2011.
  - Affiliate group reports to board, 2009-2011 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Annual conference (joint with VLA), 1998 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Annual conference, 2003 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Annual conference, 2004 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Annual conference, 2005 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Annual conference, 2006 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Annual conference, 2007 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Annual conference, 2008 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Annual conference, 2009 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Annual conference, 2010 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Annual conference, 2011 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Annual conference planning, 2004 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Annual conference planning, 2006 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Annual conference planning, 2007 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Annual conference planning, 2008 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Board meeting, January 2004 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Board meeting, April 2004 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Board meeting, September 2004 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Board meeting, November 2004 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Board meeting, January 2005 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Board meeting, April 2005 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Board meeting, September 2005 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Board meeting, November 2005 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Board meeting, January 2006 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Board meeting, April 2006 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Board meeting, September 2006 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Board meeting, October 2006 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Board meeting, January 2007 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Board meeting, April 2007 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Board meeting, September 2007 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Board meeting, October 2007 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Board meetings, 2008-2009 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Board meetings, 2010-2011 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Clinch and Roanoke Regions Combined Regional Meeting, 12 March 1996 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Clinch Regional Conference, 2010 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Executive Director reports, 2009-2011 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Handbook/membership directory, 2010-2011 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Hurricane relief, 2006 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Income tax returns, 1992-2005 (Box 33, Folder 1-4)
  - Mediagram, Fall 2009-Fall 2010 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Mediagram, Winter 2010-Fall 2011 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Membership directory, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous VEMA committee reports, 2009-2011 (Box 33, Folder 8-9)
  - Policies and Procedures Handbook, 2003 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Policies and Procedures Handbook, 2005 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Potomac Regional Conference, 28 March 2009 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Recipes from the Library: Where It All Comes Together, (VEMA 2010) (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Regional directors meeting, 18 July 2004 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Regional directors meeting, 22 July 2007 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Roanoke regional conference, 29 March 2006 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Roanoke regional conference, 23 March 2009 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Roanoke regional conference, 22 March 2010 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - School library media specialist career brochure (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Shenandoah regional conference, 9 March 2010 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Spring regional meetings and student media festivals (brochure), 1993 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Statements of cash receipts and disbursements, 1993-1996 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Statements of cash receipts and disbursements, 1999-2006 (Box 34, Folder 10-11)
  - Treasurer's packet, 2007-2008 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - VEMA Summer Professional Development Day: Follow the Web 2.0, 14 July 2008 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - VEMA vision, 2000, 2002 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Virginia Student Media Festival (brochure), 2004 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - York Regional Conferences, 2010-2011 (Box 34, Folder 16)